Guide to the Kathy Acker Notebooks 1968 - 1974 MSS.434
Fales Library and Special Collections
- [The Childlike Life Of The Black Tarantula: Chapters V - VI], "I Reveal The Real Story Of My Childhood!!", undated, circa 1973 September (Box 4, Folder 11)
  1 Holograph Manuscript, Collegewire Spiral Composition Book with Editing Notation; 1 Unbound Typescript
  Features: Edits, deletions, notes that develop into "Chapter V: I Explore My Miserable Childhood. I Become William Butler Yeats," "Chapter VI: The Story of My Life, I Become Marquis de Sade"; Loose Typescript, "The Childlike Life Of The Black Tarantula #6" Synopsis / Book Back Cover Mock-Up
- "The Childlike Life Of The Black Tarantula: Secret Document #1", undated, circa 1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Features: "I write down my unconscious fantasy world," short form diary-like works;"Structuristem Number Eight: Grid Sentences" Instructions & Handwritten Chart
- "The Creation (diaries)", 1972 Autumn (Box 4, Folder 13)
  1 Holograph Manuscript, Pink Dri-Point Theme Spiral Book with Editing Notation
  Features: "Gold: Songs For Jimi Hendrix," [this work also appears in unbound, typescript form in Box 1, Folder 13], "Household Objects: Breaking Up, Falling In Love, Description Of Life In NY," "Jerry, Paul, Elly, Bruce," "Sun Is Round," "The Emotions Of Everyone In America Journal, Black Jewel Cats," "What I Do And Why I Do It: The Process of Creation," short form diary-like, meditation, and poetic works
- [The Creation (diaries)]: "Breaking Up", undated, circa 1972 Autumn (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Features: Long form poetic work; This also appears in holograph manuscript form in "The Creation (diaries)," [Box 4, Folder 13]
- "The Destruction Of The US: The Burning Bombing Of America", 1971 Summer - 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  1 Bound Typescript Collection, Black Spring Binder with Editing Notation
  Features: "The Destruction Of The US: The Burning Bombing Of America," Flyer for Acker poetry reading, artwork by Harriet Golden; Over twenty long & short form diary-like, dream description essays & poetic works, "Diary Dreams In Night: For the Painters of Decadence for Harriet Golden," "For Lynn Lonidier," "Poems: 5/71 - 7/71," "Portraits," "Portraits: Visions,""Sequence," "Silk For Lenny"
- "The Golden Woman: Ode to Beautiful Women #1, #2, #3", undated, circa 1968 - 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Features: Short form poetic works
- "Works Done", 1968 Spring - 1972 May (Box 5, Folder 3)
  1 Bound Typescript Collection, Cream-Colored Spring Binder with Gilt Rule on Board; Editing Notation
  Features: Over twenty long & short form diary-like, dream description essays & poetic works; "Abstract Essay Collaged With Dreams," "A Ghost Story," "Communist Aesthetics," "Information Sexual Ecstasy Revolution III," "Last Poem," "Narration Of The New World," "Narrative (for Ed Klima)," "Personal Life," "Poems for Tamar 6, 7, & 8," "Political Desire: Something Beautiful For Margie," "Pornographic Poems," "Silk For Lenny," "The Betrayal Of Friends," "The Destruction Of The U.S., The Burning Bombing Of America," "The New Life," "The Parts of the Mind and How They Work," "The Worship Of Beauty Of Angels," "Velvet Awareness," "Violet Women"